# Thomas Christopher Zichko

Full-Stack Software Engineer

783 Lunar Lake Circle Cocoa, FL 32926

(931) 248-4610

chriszichkocoding@gmail.com https://zichkoding.github.io https://github.com/ZichKoding

#### **CAREER SUMMARY**

Passionate and proud Full-Stack Software Developer specializing in MERN stack and going on two years of experience in Frontend and one year experience with Backend, while leveraging my previous experiences outside of the technology field in maintenance and military to help create a more efficient, captivating, and simple user experience using MongoDB/Mongoose.js, Express.js, React, Node.js, Python 3+, Kivy 2.0+, JavaScript ES6+, HTML5, CSS3, and MySQL/Sequelize.js. I have on my own received a certificate in Scientific Computing with Python from FreeCodeCamp, and currently working on becoming a certified Full-Stack Software Developer through the University of Central Florida.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **ZichKoding**, Florida — Full-Stack Software Engineer

February 2021 - PRESENT

Creating websites and progressive web applications (PWAs) along with maintaining and updating websites and PWAs.

# **NRT Methodologies,** Cape Canaveral Space Force Station — *Lead Plant Operator*

October 2019 - PRESENT

Originally started as an assistant but the manager left, and I stepped in as a temporary Site Manager and have several documentations that the site looks and operates better than it has in years. This has led to an increase in budget to greatly improve the site for longevity.

- Ensure functionality of the SLC29 assets to enable training, technical, and intelligence opportunities through their operation.
- Regular maintenance and evaluation of the component performance of the chemical feed pumps, pressure transmitters, temperature transmitters, reactors, distillation columns, base scrubbers, temperature control units, vacuum pumps, piping, rotary evaporators, and spray dryer to name a few on the Chemical Synthesis Skids.
- Operating, diagnosing issues, and fixing issues that arise on the Chemical Synthesis Skids through Supervisory Control and Data Acquisition (SCADA) system.

## **Edpresso | Educative,** Remote — *Technical Writer*

May 2021 - Present

#### **SKILLS**

**Progressive Web Applications** 

MongoDB/Mongoose.js

Express.js

Handlebars.js

React

Node.is

Python 3+

Kivy 2.0+

JavaScript ES6+

jQuery

Jest

Bcrypt.js

CSS3

Bootstrap

HTML 5

MySQL

Sequelize.js

Git

Heroku

- Creating interactive technical documents for specific modules in Python for the students at Edpresso|Educative
- The assigned modules have been created swiftly and correctly with little to no editing from their editorial staff.
- Was recruited for this position and recruited to be on their podcast for one of the best contributors.

# **United States Marine Corps,** USA — Non-commissioned Officer/Squad Leader/Combat Engineer

January 2015 - January 2021

- Received special recognition from several major training exercises including ITX at Twenty-Nine Palms, CA, and Northern Strike in Michigan for outstanding leadership abilities.
- Trained Marines with the appropriate skills, knowledge, and abilities to do their duty as Combat Engineers execute their missions and succeed as Combat Engineers in demanding environments.
- Specialized skills in design, construction, maintenance of equipment, and demolition: Buildings, obstacles, radios, generators, motors, rockets, and all types of explosives.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **University of Central Florida**, Florida — Full-Stack Web Development

August 2021 - February 2022

• Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development from the University of Central Florida

# **FreeCodeCamp.org,** Remote — *Scientific Computing with Python*

August 2020 - February 2021

 $\bullet \ {\sf Certificate} \ {\sf in} \ {\sf Scientific} \ {\sf Computing} \ {\sf with} \ {\sf Python} \ {\sf from} \ {\sf FreeCodeCamp}$